<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>All Posts - Lachies Library</title>
        <link>https://pybrolachie.github.io/LachiesLibrary/posts/</link>
        <description>All Posts | Lachies Library</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:00:00 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pybrolachie.github.io/LachiesLibrary/posts/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Cheesymite Scrolls Recipe</title>
    <link>https://pybrolachie.github.io/LachiesLibrary/posts/cheesymite-scrolls/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Lachie</author>
    <guid>https://pybrolachie.github.io/LachiesLibrary/posts/cheesymite-scrolls/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<h3 id="info">Info:</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th style="text-align: right"></th>
          <th></th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: right">Yield:</td>
          <td>48 Scrolls</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: right">Prep time</td>
          <td>20 minutes</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: right">Cook time (pressing dough and cooking)</td>
          <td>20-25 minutes</td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>
<h3 id="equipment-required">Equipment Required:</h3>
<ul>
<li>Oven</li>
<li>several chopping boards / large plates</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="ingredients">Ingredients:</h3>
<ul>
<li>6 sheets of puff pastry</li>
<li>600g grated tasty cheese</li>
<li>half a jar of vegemite</li>
<li>2 egg yolks</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="method">Method</h3>
<ol>
<li>preheat oven to 240 degrees Celsius</li>
<li>take pastry out of the freezer about 5 minutes before use to allow the sheets to thaw a little.</li>
<li>lay the sheets out across cutting boards / plates.
<ol>
<li>if the sheets are still frozen together, use the edge of a sharp knife to leverage them apart.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>coat each sheet in a thin layer of vegemite, remember that each scroll will end up with several layers of this coating, so don&rsquo;t put it on too strong.</li>
<li>sprinkle cheese over each covered sheet of pastry.</li>
<li>roll into logs, using the egg yolk to seal them together.</li>
<li>cover each log in the remaining egg yolk</li>
<li>cut each log into 8 slices.</li>
<li>place slices on their side on a baking tray/s</li>
<li>bake for 20-25 minutes or until golden brown</li>
<li>Allow to rest and firm up outside of the oven for about 5 minutes before transferring to plates for serving</li>
</ol>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>My home PC setup</title>
    <link>https://pybrolachie.github.io/LachiesLibrary/posts/my-home-pc-setup/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Lachie</author>
    <guid>https://pybrolachie.github.io/LachiesLibrary/posts/my-home-pc-setup/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<h2 id="intro-and-disclaimer">Intro And Disclaimer</h2>
<p>Disclaimer: This is my personal setup for game development and 3D art, I obtained parts of it over a long period of time including before attending college, during my studies, and after I started working professionally. I point this out as it is important to me that anyone reading this who is interested in getting into game dev understands that they <strong>Do not</strong> need to obtain this kind of equipment to get started, I started 3D modelling on an <a href="https://browser.geekbench.com/v4/cpu/compare/179172?baseline=179172" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">old Toshiba laptop</a> with no graphics card and 4gb of DDR3 RAM, and later built a simple PC with an <a href="https://pcpartpicker.com/product/QbGj4D/intel-core-i5-7500-34ghz-quad-core-processor-bx80677i57500" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">i5-7500</a> processor and a <a href="https://www.mwave.com.au/archive/asus-geforce-gtx-1050-phoenix-2gb-video-card-ac08304" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">GTX 1050</a> graphics card which actually did quite well for a long time, so please do not let a lack of equipment prevent you from getting started.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Pizza Dough Recipie</title>
    <link>https://pybrolachie.github.io/LachiesLibrary/posts/pizza-dough-recipie/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Lachie</author>
    <guid>https://pybrolachie.github.io/LachiesLibrary/posts/pizza-dough-recipie/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<h3 id="info">Info:</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th style="text-align: right">Yield:</th>
          <th>3 pizza bases</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: right">Cook time (dough making and rising)</td>
          <td>90 minutes</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: right">Cook time (pressing dough and cooking)</td>
          <td>30 minutes</td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>
<h3 id="equipment-required">Equipment Required:</h3>
<ul>
<li>Mixer with dough hooks</li>
<li>3 stainless steel or ceramic bowls</li>
<li>plastic wrap</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="ingredients">Ingredients:</h3>
<ul>
<li>1 cup of warm water (about 40 degrees Celsius)</li>
<li>8 grams of dry yeast</li>
<li>2 teaspoons of sugar</li>
<li>1/2 teaspoon of salt</li>
<li>3 1/2 cups of plain flour</li>
<li>5 tablespoons of olive oil for cooking</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="method---creating-the-dough">Method - creating the dough</h3>
<ol>
<li>Place water, yeast, sugar, salt, and 1 cup of flour in mixing bowl, mix on lowest setting until just combined.</li>
<li>add 3 tablespoons of olive oil and 1 cup of flour, mix on medium/high for 30 seconds</li>
<li>add 1 cup of flour, mix on medium/high for 8 minutes (giving your mixer breaks based on your instruction manual).</li>
<li>During or after kneading your dough in the mixer, line up 3 bowls and use the remaining olive oil to oil up the inside of the bowls (the measurement does not need to be exact! just get a light coating on everything).</li>
<li>take your finished large ball of dough and weight on digital scale, divide into 3 roughly even portions (a few grams of is fine).
<ol>
<li>the easiest way to separate the dough is to grab 2 sections with your hands and twist, you can also cut it with a knife.</li>
<li>it is okay if you end up needing to tear some more dough of a ball to get it to get all your portions to the right weight, you can lightly knead this back together before the dough rises.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>place the 3 divided dough balls into the 3 oiled bowls, use the ball to rub the outside of the bowl, try to get the entire ball covered in oil, cover the bowls snugly with plastic wrap.</li>
<li>leave to rest for ATLEAST 1 hours.
<ol>
<li>if you like, you can put it in the fridge for 24 hours for a slow rise, the resulting dough is a bit nicer- but not by a huge amount.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ol>
<h3 id="method---working-with-the-dough">Method - working with the dough</h3>
<ol>
<li>preheat oven to 230 degrees Celsius.</li>
<li>line a pizza tray with baking paper.</li>
<li>take large cutting board and lightly coat with some of the remaining flour.</li>
<li>take a single ball of dough out of a bowl and place on the cutting board, sprinkle with some flour.
<ol>
<li>if you find the dough hard to work with, you can dust your hands with flour as well to make the slippery dough easier to handle.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>press the dough down into a disc shape, adding more flour if needed.</li>
<li>transfer the dough disc from the cutting board to the lined pizza tray, continue to press down until reaching desired size (I like a thin crust and often push mine right to the edges of a large tray to achieve this).</li>
<li>add your pizza sauce, toppings, and cheese.</li>
<li>repeat for remaining dough balls.</li>
<li>cook time varies based on pizza toppings, but typically a cook time of 12-20 minutes results in a beautiful crust and a light fluffy base.</li>
</ol>
<h3 id="notes">Notes:</h3>
<ul>
<li>for an extra crunchy crust, you can add a light brushing of olive oil to the outer rim of your pizza</li>
<li></li>
</ul>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Formatting test</title>
    <link>https://pybrolachie.github.io/LachiesLibrary/posts/formatting-test/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Lachie</author>
    <guid>https://pybrolachie.github.io/LachiesLibrary/posts/formatting-test/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>here is some text with a link to an external website</p>
<p><a href="https://lachiesteere.art/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">here is some text with a link to an external site</a></p>
<p>this note is not a real post, rather it is a test for some of the different formatting options I have here inside of obsidian, so that I can see what makes it over to html.</p>
<p><strong>Bold text</strong></p>
<p><!-- raw HTML omitted -->Underlined Text<!-- raw HTML omitted --></p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Making paper minis</title>
    <link>https://pybrolachie.github.io/LachiesLibrary/posts/making-paper-minis/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Lachie</author>
    <guid>https://pybrolachie.github.io/LachiesLibrary/posts/making-paper-minis/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p></p>
<h2 id="back-story">Back Story</h2>
<p>I’ve been playing TTRPGs (specifically D&amp;D 5e) for quite a while now, both as a player and as a DM, and combat naturally is a large part of those games, up until recently all combat I have ever played has been “theatre of the mind” and while there is nothing wrong with that (in fact in certain cases it is likely superior) I had always wanted to do tactical combat on a battle map, however as I spent many of my early D&amp;D playing years as a teenager with no disposable income – the cost for minis and maps was just too much to justify when I would often only play a few sessions a year. What is to follow is the journey of learning to make cheap paper minis (about $0.12 AUD per mini), some workflows and materials I have tried and would recommend, and some places to find resources, all things I wish I had known about back then.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>test post to push changes to other menus</title>
    <link>https://pybrolachie.github.io/LachiesLibrary/posts/test/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Lachie</author>
    <guid>https://pybrolachie.github.io/LachiesLibrary/posts/test/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>just a test</p>
<p>add some more and see</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>My First Post</title>
    <link>https://pybrolachie.github.io/LachiesLibrary/posts/my-first-post/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Lachie</author>
    <guid>https://pybrolachie.github.io/LachiesLibrary/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<h1 id="what-i-wrote-before-i-got-it-working">What I wrote before I got it working:</h1>
<p>This is my second attempt at following the network chuck video on creating a blog using obsidian, I will this time be doing more of a hybrid between what he has created, and what I want, using bits and bobs I fill out along the way. I am writing this in obsidian before I attempt to push it over to hugo and then to github sites, we shall see how it goes.</p>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
